## **COLIN BAILLIE**

## Software Engineer

- +339-927-5951
- ✓ domigan16@gmail.com
- Wakefield, MA
- www.colinbaillie.com

## EDUCATION

# UNIVERSITY OF MASSACHUSETTS LOWELL

- Bachelor of Science, Computer Science
- Degree Awarded 2014

#### MALDEN CATHOLIC HIGH SCHOOL

• Diploma Awarded 2008

### SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer striving to make deliverables on web and mobile platforms, with a strong desire to build tools that empower creatives. Working closely with product and design teams, I strive to write functional, responsive and concise code on front- and backend systems and services to meet the needs of the users and stakeholders.

As a true Greater Boston native, I currently reside in Wakefield with my wife and two children. Not only am I a software engineer, but I am also an independent music producer and DJ. I have been nominated for a Boston Music Award, released three full length albums, and many EPs and singles. My other hobbies include snowboarding, golf, disc golf, viewing fine film and television, and travelling with my family.

## ACCOLADES

- Awarded Eagle Scout Rank, Troop 728 Reading, MA, 2008
- Boston Music Award Nominee, 2023

## SKILLS

- Native in React, Typescript, Javascript, SQL, Node.js, Next.js
- · Highly skilled with npm, Git, VS Code, Docker, AWS
- Previous experience in Java, C/C++, C#, Python, PHP
- Highly experienced in relational database modeling, strong grasp of design patterns and best practices, as well as web application modeling and design

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### 1up Health

OCT 2024 - APR 205

Senior Front-End Software Engineer

 Contributed to a new console application that allowed users to interact with the FHIR (fast health interoperability resource) API to search patient records

#### Cinapse

JAN 2022 - MAY 2024

Senior Software Engineer

- Built a complex web application for assistant directors and production managers on film and television production sets to schedule their shoots
- Built application mainly in Node.JS with TypeScript, React, Next.js,
  Prisma and PostgreSQL
- Contributed to building real-time collaboration within the app, the "day out of days" scheduling algorithm, and reporting features that allowed the user to print and save custom formatted full-color schedules

#### Reggora

AUG 2020 - DEC 2021

Senior Software Engineer

- Contributed new features on multiple platforms used by lenders and appraisers using Python, React, mongoDB
- Participated in a support team for solving real-time issues experienced by clients

#### **SyncOnSet**

JUL 2018 - JUL 2020

Software Engineer

- Contributed to re-writing software used by major television and motion picture studios on the sets of high-budget productions using Agile development process
- Developed primarily in React, using Typescript, Redux, Hapi, Node.js, npm, mySQL & Docker
- Worked closely with product owner to develop and implement UX/UI using Zepplin.io
- Maintained legacy budgeting application in PHP using the Yii framework

#### **EF Go Ahead Tours**

JUN 2016 - JUN 2018

Software Engineer

- Worked with a team to develop and maintain front-end capabilities for a travel website, primarily using React, Redux, Bootstrap, Node.js & npm libraries
- Contributed to back-end layer in C#, .NET Core, & Elasticsearch, using MongoDB and SQL databases